MERON HAYLE

Full Stack Engineer

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Nairobi Kenya

PHONE

0748828469

EMAIL

hayle.meron13@gmail.com

LINKS

Personal Blog

LinkedIn

SKILLS

Golang

Java

Python

Angular

React

SQL

Postgresql

Kubernetes

PROFILE

I have been working in the IT sector for +6 years, on different kinds of projects and I have really enjoyed it so far. I define myself as a fast learner, detail-oriented, and responsible engineer. Learning new technologies and then being able to apply them to innovate or improve projects is very satisfying. I like to be a part of a team willing to build solutions that make a difference.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full Stack Engineer, The CADS

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Sep 2020 — Present

My role as a full stack engineer at The CADS is to enable the team to create innovative products and services. As a full-stack engineer, I am responsible for all aspects of product development, from research and design to development and testing. I work closely with Product Management, Engineering, and other teams across the organization to ensure that our work is aligned with business objectives and customer needs.

Some other misc projects in which I'm active are maintaining and deploying the ELK stack for us to manage logs for the services that we have and deploying Prometheus and Grafana to monitor our clusters.

We also rely on Redis for caching thus I'm also responsible to identify endpoints and or services that need caching on a weekly basis and implementing caching for them.

Flutter Full Stack Developer, LTRconnect

May 2021 — Sep 2021

As a lead developer for Flutter, I was responsible for the development of our front-end application. I have worked with our team to create an interface that is intuitive and easy to use.

My role involves creating database models that encapsulate all of the necessary information about our app. I also developed and tested the flutter application and ensure that these models are in sync with other teams.

Docker
Django
RethinkDb
Flutter
Apache
Redis
RabbitMQ
GCP, Azure, AWS
HTML/CSS/JavaScript

LANGUAGES

English

Tigrinya

Worked as a full-stack developer for mobile development with flutter and Go.

- Lead a small team to plan, develop, test, and deploy a flutter-based project.
- created the backbone schema for the project and maintained the Go back-end service.

https://ltrconnect.com/

Full Stack Developer, XelphaHealth

Austin, Texas

Apr 2018 — Feb 2021

As a backend engineer, I was responsible for building out the infrastructure of the company. This involved everything from databases to messaging systems to security measures.

As a frontend engineer, I was responsible for building out the UI/UX of our products. This included everything from designing and implementing iconography to creating wireframes and prototypes.

As a full stack engineer, I was responsible for all aspects of my team's product development process—from writing code to testing, deploying, and maintaining our product as it evolved over time.

Full Stack Developer, FidemStore

Nairobi, Kenya

Feb 2021 — Aug 2021

Logistics Platform

Responsibility:

- Designed and implemented Database structure, and user interfaces(UI).
- · Performed Unit Tests.
- Programming Languages: Angular 2 (front-end), Go (back-end),
 PostgreSQL (SQL db)
- · Platform: Linux

Link: https://staging.fidem.store/

Full Stack Developer, TukTukRide (Self Employed)

Nairobi, Kenya

Mar 2019 — Dec 2020

A Mobile native ride-hailing application development.

Sneak-peek: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qCbINcPNLus

- Designed and implemented back end and front end functionality.
- · Performed Unit Test.
- Programming Language and Framework: Flutter and Golang (Backend Services).
- Used: Visual Studio Code, PostgreSQL, Rethink Db, Firebase service.

Full Stack Developer, HabeshaExpress

Nairobi

Feb 2018 — Jan 2021

Currency Exchange platform

Responsibility:

- Designed and implemented Database structure, PHP connectivity, and user interfaces(UI).
- · Performed Unit Test.
- Programming Language: SQL, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, j Query, CSS (Twitter Bootstrap)
- · Used: Visual Studio Code, PHPMyAdmin, MariaDB
- · Platform: Linux

Link: https://www.habeshaexpress.com

Part Time Instructor, Mahta Electronics Training Center

Asmara

Jun 2012 — Nov 2016

Worked as Electronics and Computer Software Instructor.

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science, Eritrea Institute of Technology

Asmara

Jun 2011 — Sep 2015

BS in Computer Science, Eritrean Institute of Technology,

Asmara Eritrea, GPA - 3.62 / 4.0

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2021 Architect Professional

Mar 2022

See Credential

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2021 Architect Associate

Feb 2022

See Credential

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate

Jan 2022

See Credential